Guide to the Myron Genel, Associate Dean, School of Medicine, Yale University, records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Myron Genel, Associate Dean, School of Medicine, Yale University, records
1981-2005
RU 1131
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.75
(11 boxes)
The records of Myron Genel, Associate Dean of Government and Community Affairs, School of Medicine, Yale University consist of Dean's Operating Group meeting minutes and chronological files, meeting ephemera and correspondence from the Health Policy Journal club, Board of Director records, correspondence and Planning Committee records of the Hill Development Corporation, minutes of the Medical School Council Steering Committee, grant and health reports of the Minority Health Coalition and facilities and financial records, and actions plans of the Yale Psychiatric Institute.
Yale University. School of Medicine
Scope and Contents
The records of Myron Genel, Associate Dean of Government and Community Affairs, School of Medicine, Yale University consist of Dean's Operating Group meeting minutes and chronological files, meeting ephemera and correspondence from the Health Policy Journal club, Board of Director records, correspondence and Planning Committee records of the Hill Development Corporation, minutes of the Medical School Council Steering Committee, grant and health reports of the Minority Health Coalition and facilities and financial records, and actions plans of the Yale Psychiatric Institute.
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-B (YRG 27-B), Records of deputy, associate, and assistant deans of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
These records are restricted as established by Yale Corporation regulations. Please refer to http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives for more details about these policies.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Medical education -- United States; Medicine -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records, 1981-2005; Accession 2015-A-008
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2040
  - General files
    - Affirmative action, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Affirmative action meeting, 1989 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alumni Affairs, Office of, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Council on Government Affairs (CoGA), 1992 January 5-1992 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Department of Motor Vehicles, organ donation calendar, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Health Management Forum, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Human Resources, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ivy Group conference, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Labor, health and human services, education, and related agencies, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Medical education, Yale system etc., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Massachusetts Society for Medical Research (MSMR) dinner, 1992 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Neuroendocrine program, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Pew Health Professions Commission, 1991-2005 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Pew Rockefeller grant, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Robert Wood Johnson Community Award-Elsie W. Cofield, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Yale Teachers Institute, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dean's Operating Group
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 23-25)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
  - Facilities
    - City Approvals Committee, 1988 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Facilities Protection Bill, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Facilities renewal project-Leon Rosenberg (LER) letter, 1990 May (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Greiner report-parking, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Howard Avenue garage, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Lot 5 projects, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Low-level radioactive waste (LLRW)
      - General files
        - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - 1992 January-March (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - 1992 May (Box 2, Folder 8A)
        - 1992 May-July (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Disposal (AB 6985), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Nuclear waste/incinerator, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Seamco radioactive waste storage, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Radionuclide Federal Register (FR) notice-Nuclear Regulatory Commission/Environmental Protection Agency, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Waste-radioactive low-level, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Medical Center approvals, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Parking garage, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Parking meetings, 1987 November (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Yale-New Haven Medical Center Inc., 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Fetal tissue research
    - National Institute of Health reauthorization/Senate, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Research Freedom Act of 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Udall/others-fetal tissue research, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Health Policy Journal
    - Club meetings
      - 1987 December 7 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - 1988 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - 1988 February-March (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - 1988 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - 1988 June 6 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - 1988 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - 1988 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - 1989 January 9 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - 1989 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - 1989 March 6 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - 1989 April 3 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - 1989 June 5 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - 1989 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - 1989 October 13 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - 1989 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - 1990 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - 1990 February 5 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - 1990 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - 1990 April 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1990 May 14 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 1990 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 1990 November 5 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - 1990 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - 1991 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - 1991 February 4 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 1991 March 4 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - 1991 April 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - 1991 May 6 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 1991 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - 1991 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - 1991 November 4 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 1991 December 9 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 1992 January 6 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - 1992 February 3 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - 1992 March 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - 1992 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - 1992 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 18A)
      - 1992 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 18B)
      - 1992 November 2 (Box 3, Folder 18C)
      - 1992 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 18D)
      - 1993 January 11 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - 1993 February 8 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - 1993 March 8 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - 1993 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - 1993 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - 1993 October 11 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - 1993 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - 1994 January 10 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - 1994 February 14 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - 1994 March 14 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - 1994 April 11 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - 1994 June 6 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - 1994 September 19 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - 1994 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - 1994 November 14 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - 1994 December 19 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - 1995 January 9 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - 1995 February 13 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - 1995 March 13 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - 1995 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - 1995 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - 1995 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - 1995 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - 1995 November 6 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - 1995 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - 1996 January 8 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - 1996 February 12 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - 1996 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - 1996 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - 1996 May 13-16 (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - 1996 June 3 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - 1996 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - 1996 October 14 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - 1996 November 4 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - 1996 December 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1997 January 13 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1997 February 10 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1997 March 10 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 1997 April 14 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 1997 May 12 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 1997 August 12 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 1997 September 9 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - 1997 October 7 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - 1997 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - 1997 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - 1998 January 12-14 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - 1998 February 9 (Box 4, Folder 12A)
      - 1998 February 12 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - 1998 March 2 (Box 4, Folder 13A)
      - 1998 April 6 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - 1998 April 14 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - 1998 May 11-14 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - 1998 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Hill Development Corporation
    - General files, 1987-1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Board of Directors and officers, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Clippings, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence
      - 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - 1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Detoxification Center, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Development-New Haven, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Planning Committee, 1991 February-June (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
    - Schnip Development Corporation partnership, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Medical School Council
    - Steering Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minority Health Coalition
    - Black and minority health, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Grant application, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Health and Human Services (HHS), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Meetings
      - 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
      - 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - 1987 June (Box 5, Folder 7A)
      - 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - National Association of Biomedical Research (NABR) correspondence
    - 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Rosenberg (Leon) files
    - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Dean's message, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Dean's report, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Minorities address, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Steering Committee on Animal Research
    - Advisory Committee on Animals in Research, 1987-1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Animals in research-letters from students, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Buckshire/People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Meetings
      - 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - 1994 June 21 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - 1994 September 27 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - 1995 January (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - 1995 April 11 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - 1995 July 18 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - 1995 October 3 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - 1996 January 30 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - 1996 April 23 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) response, 1995 April 21 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Task Force on Animal Research, 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 29-31)
    - United States Drug Administration (USDA) citation, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Strategic Planning Task Force, 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Yale Psychiatric Institute
    - Affirmative action, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 2A)
    - Affirmative action faculty practice plan, 1984 November-1986 February (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Connecticut Cost Commission, 1985 May-1986 March (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Connecticut Mental Health Center state audit, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Fact sheet, 1985 October (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Health Systems Agency, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Hill Development Corporation/community liaison, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Land disposition, 1986-1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1985 October-1986 May (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Re-development agency, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Task Force correspondence-Board of Aldermen, 1985 August-1988 June (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Taxes and facilities correspondence, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Training program for mental health workers, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Records, 1987-2003; Accession 2017-A-047
  Restricted until January 1, 2039
  - Administrative files
    - Animal research
      - Animal care, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Dean's message on animal rights, 1989 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Animal rights demonstration, 1989 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Demonstrations, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Death of rhesus monkeys, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Press conferences, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Ida protests, 1989 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Yale animal research, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Animal cruelty articles, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Animals in education, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Primate liberation week, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Community service, 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dean's operating group minutes, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Graduate medical education, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Medicolegal grand rounds, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - National Association for Biomedical Research (NABR) response to proposed regulations, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Office of Government and Community Affairs (OGCA) Annual report, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Town meetings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence
    - Dean's office, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
    - Head injury research, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Steering Committee-Animal Research
    - Meetings
      - 1996 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - 1997 February 4 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 1997 June 3 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - 1997 December 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - 1998 June 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 1998 November 24 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - 1999 February 16 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1999 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1999 December 13 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 2000 June 5 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 2002 April (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 2003 June 3 (Box 4, Folder 7)